Guide to the Mitchell Family collection BCMS.0086
Brooklyn Collection
Mitchell Family collection
1910-1982
Center for Brooklyn History
Diamantis, Edward
Mitchell Family
BCMS.0086
0.9 Linear Feet in 2 document boxes
Photographs, papers and bound volumes mostly pertaining to the Junk and Mitchell family and their properties.
Biographical Note
Mary Junk and Arthur Ballon Mitchell were married in 1932. Arthur appears to have died in the last days of 1939. Mary Mitchell's maiden name was Junk; the McEvoys, another family represented in the collection, may have been related to the Mitchells or the Junks. During their married life, the Mitchells lived at 3960 Glenwood St, Little Neck, Queens, with their two mothers—Ada R. Mitchell and Margaret Williams (formerly Junk). Arthur was employed by the Julius Forstmann Corporation. During the 1930s Arthur was the subject of an IRS audit. After Arthur's untimely death, Mary purchased a house in Bay Ridge, Brooklyn. Mortgage receipts attest to the ongoing payments on the property. The house may have been a two-family as various documents refer to "tenants." After the death of Mary Mitchell circa 1984, the property was passed to Lucy O'Shea, and then to the Diamantis family.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series by type.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edward and Beth Diamantis, May 2005.
Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y); Home ownership |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Black-and-white prints (photographs); Color prints (photographs); Printed ephemera; Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Diamantis, Edward
- Documents and ephemera
  - Mortgage payment slips, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Made out to Mary Mitchell from Home Owners' Loan Corporation and Dime Savings Bank on house at 446-76th Street, Bay Ridge. Also includes correspondence.
  - Correspondence with IRS and tax returns, 1935-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Addressed to Arthur Mitchell at 3960 Glenwood St, Little Neck, NY.
  - Home owners insurance certificates, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence relating to purchase of house at 446 76th Street, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Materials relating to the death of Arthur Mitchell, 1940 January (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Condolence letter, life insurance policy and funeral receipts.
  - 446 76th Street receipts and contract, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Relates to installation of basement room.
  - Arthur and Mary Mitchell life insurance receipts, 1933-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cancelled checks, 1946, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Written by Mary Mitchell to various businesses.
  - Postcards, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Two postcards from "Susie" to Mary Mitchell.
  - Recipe booklets and 'Bake-o-meter', circa 1947-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Recipe clippings, notes, and ephemera, circa 1931-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mass cards, prayers, circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - War ration books (Box 1, Folder 13)
    For Mary Mitchell, Sev Samuelsen and Anders A. Bjune, 446 76th Street.
  - Ephemera and clippings, circa 1942-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Visiting cards for Miss Mary Junk (Mary Mitchell), reduced fare card for Lucy O'Shea (Lindsay Administration), newspaper clippings.
  - Other property, 1910, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    For sale announcement for property at New Cassel, NY owned by Mrs. Mary Mitchell. Also a deed from Ada Mitchell to her daughter Edna Mitchell, dated June 15, 1910, transferring any rights in property previously owned by John Mitchell (d. 10 Feb 1897) and bequeathed by him to his son William E. Mitchell, husband of Ada.
  - McEvoy certificates and letter, 1900-1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    McEvoy family certificates, graduation, life insurance (circa 1900-1912) and one letter (1945).
  - Autograph book, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Belonging to Nanette A. Hall.
  - Date book (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Recording deaths, births, marriages.
- Photographs
  - People in living room, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - People outside house, 1943-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Various people (tenants?) outside of a yellow brick row house in Bay Ridge. Some feature a black spaniel.
  - Mary and Arthur Mitchell, 1932-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cats, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mixed photographs, circa 1920s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Three photographs, one of a group of young women gathered around a pony. Note on folder "photos inc the foster girl."
  - Mary and Arthur Mitchell wedding photographs and invitation, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Marriage of Arthur Mitchell and Mary.
  - Photograph album, 1920-1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Snapshots of unnamed people and their many named spaniels. Places mentioned: Long Beach, Little Neck, Beach Lake PA.
  - Small photograph album (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Subjects unnamed except for one, "J. Vickers."